

Mike Tkachuk

Web Developer

402 Royal York Road, Etobicoke, ON, Canada, Apt 3, Etobicoke, ON, ON, M8Y 2R5, Canada

https://mike-developer.ca/

MT2314

in mike-tkachuk-82909111a

Nov 1993

tkachuk2314@gmail.com

16474105436

Practiced Full Stack Developer with proven experience developing interactive components and web application within an AGILE environment. Solution-driven and adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining the best way forward. Built products for desktop and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and accessibility using a variety of technologies, frame works and libraries. I am comfortable using API's, third-party integrations as well as managing both SQL and NoSQL databases. Trained in the MERN stack with a mobile first approach.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Schemas

HTML5, CSS3, JSON, XML, AJAX, JavaScript, SQL, MQL, REST, GraphQL

*(some Python and PHP)

Frameworks and Libraries

Node.js, React JS, Express.js, Next.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Jest, Auth0, Passport

Tools & Technologies

Postman, Git, Developer Tools, NPM, Yarn, Firebase, AWS, Vercel, MongoDB Atlas, Auth0, Passport, Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Adobe Acrobat, Figma,

WORK EXPERIENCE

TVO

(May 2021 - Present)

Ellis Don/ Oxford

(Nov 2018 - May 2021)

Web Production Artist

- Built e-learning courses for the Ontario Ministry of Education and for the TVO platform
- Developed and maintained interactive objects using React and Sass within a micro frontend as a part of the Web Solutions team
- Created and maintained tools and resources to help various teams with their processes using a variety of technologies and languages including Visual Basic, Python, NodeJS, Power Automate and others.

Shop Lead

- Coordinate daily work strategies to construct and transport hoist construction materials to construction sites around the GTA.
- Adjusted job assignments and schedules to keep pace with dynamic business needs, factoring in processes, employee knowledge and construction site demands
- Operating machinery and leading small detailing teams towards job completion and training employees as machine operators

EDUCATION

Humber College

Diploma, Electro-Mechanical Engineering Robotics and Automation

(Dec 2014 - Mar 2016)

University Of Toronto

(Sep 2020 - Apr 2020)

Bootcamp, Full Stack Web Development

PROJECTS

Employee Management System

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, HandleBars, OAuth, mySQL, third party API

Collaboration aimed at easing the management of employees and jobs. Allows the user to create teams, assign jobs and track job progress.

Employee Databse Search

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, third party API

A search directory system that allows the user to search for a specific employee with automatic results.

Story Books

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, OAuth

A social platform designed for users to create stories which they can either save or share with other users.